# **SHRUTI SUMAN**

LinkedIn | GitHub | Leetcode

Location: Lower parel, Mumbai,India Email: shrutisuman034@gmail.com | Mobile: 6376231630

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

A **dedicated programmer** with an aim to achieve a challenging and prestigious position in a reputed organization and utilize my knowledge of **data structure and algorithms and problem-solving skills** to contribute to the organization's growth and also expand my knowledge and experience.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Software Engineer-1** 

Sep 2023–Present Onsite – Mumbai, India

HomeVille Group Pvt Ltd

- I am working as Backend-Developer in BHN (Bharat-Housing Network Which is our main Co-leading platform.
- Working Skills Php, Laravel, Laragon SQL, Git, Gitbash.
- API intergation and Creating API and Adding New features in API and fetch the data from Database making Blade file(view module).

#### **EX-EXPERIENCE**

**Teaching Assistance** 

**Coding Ninjas** 

May 2021 – Aug 2021 Remote – Delhi, India

- \* Key responsibilities during the internship were **Taking doubt sessions**
- \* Debugging codes DSA and Problem solving My overall Rating is 4.5 out of 5

## **EDUCATION**

Chandigarh University

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

XIIth

K.N INTER COLLEGE (BSEB)

Xth

Shanti Niketan Shikshan Sansthan (CBSE)

Overall CGPA: 7.3 july 2019 – july 2023

Percentage: 70

Apr 2018 – May 2019

CGPA: 9.4 Apr 2015– May 2016

## **PROJECTS**

**Task Manager** 

HTML,CSS,Node.js, Express,MongoDB, APIs,JavaScript, Github

SourceLink

\* A **CRUD application** exposed using a RESTFUL API made with Node.js. It is list user can save their task and description accordingly with time and delete their task as per user need and add another new task.

Teerexshop-App

HTML, CSS, TypeScript,Angular,APIs Github

SourceLink

- \* Developed a user-friendly e-commerce UI that allows customers to browse, search, and filter t-shirts by various attributes, such as **name**, **color**, **type**, **and gender**.
- \* Shopping cart feature that allows **users to add multiple T-shirts**, view their cart, modify quantities, and see the total amount of their orders.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Languages** : C, C++, JavaScript, Familiar(Java), HTML, CSS,TypeScript.

**Frameworks** : Angular, Express.js, Node.js, REST APIs, Bootstrap.

**Databases** : MongoDB, SQL.

**Fundamental**: DBMS, Operating System, OOP, LINUX, WINDOW.

Interpersonal

Skills

: Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Optimization.

**Dev Tools** : Visual Studio Code, Git.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

• Certification Of Coding Ninjas Web Development

• Excellence Certification Of DSA